Finding Aid for the Carol Burnett Papers PASC.0066
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Artwork (box 6), 1964-2003; Series 4.
  - Illustrated caricatures of Carol Burnett, 1964, undated; 1 8"x10", drawing, b/w; 1 9"x9" drawing, color (Box 22, Folder 12)
    B/w illustration of Carol Burnett by Bob Levy, 1964; the color illustration/cartoon of Carol Burnett by Bill Brown, undated.
  - Portrait illustrations, [1981]; 3 illustrations; 20"x24", color pastel (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Portrait illustrations of Carol Burnett.
- Awards and Certificates, 1963-2002; Series 5.; 1 manuscript box; 3 legal boxes; 1 flat box
  This series consists of various awards and certificates honoring Carol Burnett, as well as press clippings and photographs related to such events. Materials include: the People's Choice honoring Carol Burnett as Favorite Female Entertainer of the Year (1976-81); photographs of the Peabody Award (1963); press clippings for Harvard University's Hasty Pudding Award (1969); Emmy Nominations (1994-1995; 2001-2002); and humanitarian/charity awards such as March of Dimes and Hemophilia Foundations.
  Content arranged in chronological order.
  - UCLA Medal, Presented by the Chancellor, undated; Plastic encased medal (Box 63)
    Contains UCLA Medal, Presented by the Chancellor.
  - Peabody Award, 1963; 3 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 49, Folder 24)
    Contains photographs of Carol Burnett with her Peabody medal and several unidentified men.
  - Outer Circle, citation of honor, 1964; Matted letter (Box 32, Folder 7)
    Contains matted letter of "citation to honor" Carol Burnett's performance in the Broadway production of Fade Out, Fade In. Presented by Outer Circle, Organization of Writers on the New York Theatre for Out-of-Town Newspapers and National Productions.
  - Decree, Keeper of the Seal, June 24, 1965; 1 letter; 1 decree, 11"x14" (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Contains a "decree" issued to Carol Burnett for being "A Legend in Her Own Time" from J. Akuhead Puple, KGU, Honolulu, Hawaii (NBC affiliate radio station). Enclosed is letter of congratulations from Puple that accompanied decree.
  - Comedy Star of the Year, The Photoplay Magazine Medal, 1967-1972; 4 medals in plastic plaque (Box 63)
    Contains 4 Photoplay Magazine Medals awarded to Carol Burnett for Comedy Star of the Year.
  - Santa's Favorite Helper, Award, [1968]; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 14)
    Contains paper award/postcard given to Carol Burnett for being Santa's Favorite Helper.
  - Press clippings, Hasty Pudding Award, 1969; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 44, Folder 10)
    Contains press clippings for Harvard University's Hasty Pudding Award for Woman of the Year bestowed to Carol Burnett.
  - National Academy of Television Arts and Science, 1972; Medal (Box 63)
    Contains medal given to Carol Burnett from the National Academy of Television Arts and Science in recognition of their 25th Anniversary.
  - Awards, 1974; 1 folder
    Contains two awards given to Carol Burnett: Certificate of Merit, in recognition of "Her Friendly Smile" awarded by Hollencrest Intermediate School (March 1, 1974); Decency in Entertainment Award awarded by Notre Dame Club of Chicago (March 26, 1974).
    Record was entered without box/folder information, not sure where this material is located.
  - Photograph, Hollywood Star, [1974]; 2 photographs; 8" x 10", color (Box 60, Folder 21)
    Contains photograph of Carol Burnett's Hollywood star and photograph of theater that Burnett was fired from as a young person. Photographs are annotated in Burnett's handwriting: (photo of theater) "The Old Warners/now Pacific on Hollywood Bl/Wilcox"; (photo of star) "Sweet Revenge-in front of the theater where I was fired." Star was awarded to Burnett in 1974.
  - Salute to Carol Burnett Hemophilia Foundation, 1974; Program book (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Program for the Salute to Carol Burnett [by the] Hemophilia Foundation that contains information on foundation; separate sheet with guest list for event.
  - Salute to Carol Burnett, Hemophilia Foundation of Southern California, October 30, 1974; Silver and plastic plaque (Box 64)
    Contains a plaque acknowledging The 5th Dimension's Salute to Carol Burnett, Hemophilia Foundation of Southern California.
  - Louella Parsons Award, Hollywood Women's Press Club, 1979; Plaque (Box 64)
    Contains the Louella Parsons Award given to Carol Burnett by the Hollywood Women's Press Club "For Presenting the Best Hollywood Image to the World."
  - March of Dimes Jack Benny Memorial Award, 1981; 2 program books, b/w (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Program for the March of Dimes Jack Benny Memorial Award given to Carol Burnett by the March of Dimes Birth Defects Foundation. Program contains congratulations from well-known industry people such as Julie Andrews, Dean Martin and Mike Douglas.
  - International Radio and Television Society Inc., Gold Medal, February 28, 1984; 1 folder, 11"x 14" (Box 32, Folder 8)
    Gold Medal award given to Carol Burnett from the International Radio and Television Society Inc.
  - UCLA Medal, June 16, 1985; Award; 11" x 14" (Box 32, Folder 9)
    Contains UCLA Medal award (paper)in padded vinyl, interior cloth, folder. Presented to Carol Burnett by Chancellor Charles E. Young for her contribution to education, arts, and children, and for her achievements in television, theatre and film.
  - The Soap Opera Awards, January 1988; Upright plaque (Box 62)
    Contains a Soap Opera Award given to Carol Burnett.
  - Emmy Award Nominations, 1994-1995; 2001-2002; 2 paper certificates; 12 1/4" x9 1/2"; 8 1/2"x11" (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Contains 2001-2002 Emmy nomination for Outstanding Variety, Music or Comedy Special to Carol Burnett for the program "The Carol Burnett Show, 'Show Stoppers'"; 1994-1995 Emmy nomination for Outstanding Individual Performance in a Variety or Music Program to Carol Burnett for the program "Men, Movies and Carol."
  - Producers Guild of America, March 2, 1994; Paper award (Box 26, Folder 2)
    This folder contains the paper award from the Producers Guild of America (PGA) to Carol Burnett and the Carol Burnett Show on their induction into the PGA Hall of Fame.
  - Women in Film, Lucy Award, 1997; Upright plaque (Box 62)
    Contains a Women in Film, Lucy Award given to Carol Burnett.
  - Garland for Performance (Putting it Together), Back Stage West, 1998; Plastic award (Box 64)
    Contains award given to Carol Burnett by Back Stage West for her performance in Putting it Together.
  - Regents' Professor/Director Honor, March 1999; Plaque (Box 63)
    Contains plaque from UCLA School of Arts and Architecture honoring Carol Burnett as a Regents' Professor/Director for the production of Once Upon a Mattress.
  - Library of Congress, Living Legend, 2000; Medal in wood case (Box 63)
    Contains Library of Congress, Living Legend medal awarded to Carol Burnett.
- Photographs, 1940s-2003; Series 6.; 9 manuscript boxes; 3 flat boxes
  This series contains photographs that are not of specific television shows or stage/live performance, but instead taken at events or off-set at personal gatherings.
  Contents arranged chronologically by decades.
  - Carol Burnett, b&w (Box 39)
  - Carol Burnett with Zero Mostel and Lucille Ball, b&w (Box 39)
  - Photographs: 1940s, Subseries 1.; 1 boxes
    Contents arranged in chronological order.
    This sub-series contains assorted photographs from the 1940s.
    - Film studio [MGM] group photo, 1940s; 1 photograph; 9"x14", b/w (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Group photograph of major actors/actresses at film studio [MGM]. Individuals photograph include: Gene Kelly, Judy Garland, Fred Astaire, Jennifer Jones, Ethel Barrymore.
  - Photographs: 1950s, Subseries 2.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains assorted photographs from the 1950s.
    - Photographs, early 1950s; 7 photographs; various sizes, b/w & color (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Contains production stills of unidentified performance; Love Thy Coach; portrait of Carol Burnett.
    - Photographs, early 1950s; 2 folders; 25 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Contains photographs of Carol Burnett during her late teenage years and early 20s. Photos of her with unidentified young people in social gatherings; with unidentified theater group; UCLA theater performances (homecoming show, Love Thy Coach); production stills of Stumptown Players; Rehearsal Club Revue.
    - Group photograph, 1950s; 1 photograph; 11"x14", color (Box 24, Folder 10)
      Contains group (possibly youth theater group) photograph; Carol Burnett in middle, wearing black dress.
    - Portrait photographs, 1955, 1958; 18 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Contains assorted portrait photographs of Carol Burnett alone, with her dog and with first husband Don Saroyan. Two photographs are signed by Burnett.
    - Life Magazine, September 15, 1959; 3 photographs; 9"x13", b/w (Box 24, Folder 7)
      Contains production stills of Carol Burnett performing for a group of unidentified women. Description on back of photos: "Property of Life Magazine; Story & Location: Carol Burnette [sic] on T.V.; 9-15-59."
  - Photographs: 1960s, Subseries 3.; 2 manuscript boxes; 2 flat boxes
    This sub-series contains assorted photographs from the 1960s.
    - Portrait photographs, [early 1960s]; 2 folders; 7 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 49, Folder 16)
      Contains two different portrait photographs of Carol Burnett made into postcards.
    - Photographic slides, [early 1960s]; 6 photographic slides; 2 1/4" x 2 1/4", color (Box 24, Folder 12)
      Contains slides of Carol Burnett in a variety of portrait poses; slides in black mounting material.
    - Head shots, Carol Burnett, [1960s]; 7 photos; 11"x14", b/w (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Contains large portrait photographs, in various poses/settings (outside with tree; in studio). There are also 8"x10" copies of the same photos available in this sub-series.
    - Photographs, John Thomas Dye School, [1960s]; 6 photos; 10"x14", b/w (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Contains photographs of Los Angeles based John Thomas Dye School (kindergarten-6th); photos include campus grounds, buildings and an outdoor recreational fair/festival. No identifiable individuals.
    - Photographs, [1960s]; 2 folders; 38 photographs; various sizes, b/w, color (Box 49, Folder 21)
      Contains various photographs of Carol Burnett on and off-stage at different unidentified events/performances.
    - Photographs, [1960s]; 20 photographs; varous sizes, b/w, color (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Photographs, [1960s]; 16 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Photographs, [1960s]; 19 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 60, Folder 1)
      Contains various photographs of Carol Burnett on and off-stage at different unidentified events/performances. Some photographs include Joe Hamilton.
    - Photographs, [1960s]; 19 photographs; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 60, Folder 2)
      Contains various photographs of Carol Burnett on and off-stage at different unidentified events/performances. Also included photograph of Burnett with Steve Rossi and Marty Allen.
    - Photographs, [1960s]; 10 photographs; 8"x10" b/w (Box 60, Folder 3)
      Contains various photographs of Carol Burnett on and off-stage at different unidentified events/performances. Also includes photograph of Burnett and Jim Nabors.
    - Portrait Photographs, [1960s]; 13 photographs; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 49, Folder 17)
      Contains various portrait photographs of Carol Burnett.
    - Portrait photographs, [1960s]; 15 photographs; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Portrait photographs, [1960s]; 10 photographs, 1 slide; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 49, Folder 19)
      Contains photographs of Carol Burnett having her portrait painted; includes photograph of finished portrait painting; and slide of painting.
    - Portrait photographs, [1960s]; 5 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 49, Folder 20)
      Contains proof sheets of Carol Burnett in costume portraits (movie star, Tarzan).
    - Unidentified woman, [1960s]; 1 photograph; 11" x 14", b/w (Box 24, Folder 16)
      Contains photograph of unidentified woman.
    - Neiman-Marcus window display, July 18, 1962; 6 photographs; 8" x 10", b/w (Box 49, Folder 12)
      Contains photographs of a Neiman-Marcus (Dallas, TX) window display featuring photographs of Carol Burnett. Folder also contains business card of "Mrs. Sara Woods Marshall Director of Public Relations Neiman-Marcus."
    - Photographs, mid-late 1960s; Photographs, various sizes (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Contains photographs include: 1, 11"x14", b/w of Carol Burnett in caricature as a choir leader and as the five choir singers; 2, 10 1/2"x10 1/2", b/w posing in a wax museum-type diorama exhibit; 1, 11"x14", color cut out of Burnett's face on different woman's body in bikini; 1, 11'x14", b/w of Burnett reading letter.
  - Photographs 1970s, Subseries 4.; 2 manuscript boxes; 1 flat box
    This sub-series contains assorted photographs from the 1970s.
    - Photographs, 1970s; 4 photographs; various sizes; 35mm color slides (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Photographs include: 1, 11"x14", color of Carol Burnett and Susan Dey; 3, 11"x14", color of Burnett rehearsing alone on a stage; 35mm color slides of these stage photos; 2 slides of outdoor horse event (only these are dated November 1973).
    - Photographs, [1970s]; 12 photographs; various sizes, b/w, color (Box 60, Folder 7)
      Contains various photographs of Carol Burnett on and off-stage at different unidentified events/performances. Includes photographs of Joe Hamilton, George Kennedy, The Pointer Sisters, Walter Matthau.
    - Photographic slide, [1970s]; 1 photographic slide; 35 mm, color (Box 60, Folder 9)
      Contains one slide of Carol Burnett.
    - Photographic slides, [1970s]; 35 photographics slides; 35 mm, color (Box 60, Folder 10)
      Contains slides of Carol Burnett poising as individual astrological signs.
    - Portrait Photograph, [1970s]; 1 photograph; 13" x 10", color (Box 24, Folder 14)
      Contains portrait of Carol Burnett dressed as a clown.
      Color photo is fading.
    - Portrait photographs, [1970s]; 2 matted photographs; 14 1/2"x14 1/2", color (Box 39, Folder 1)
      Contains portrait photographs of Carol Burnett.
    - Portrait photographs, [1970s]; 4 photorgraphs; 14"x17", color (Box 39, Folder 2)
      Contains matted portrait photographs of Carol Burnett.
    - Photograph, 1973; 2 photograph; 8"x10", b/w (Box 60, Folder 8)
      Contains photographs of Carol Burnett and two unidentified men. Photographs were originally attached to enclosed business card: "Beverly Edwards Public Relations The Beverly Hills Hotel 'Many thanks for your cooperation! Bev'."
    - Blackglama Story, photographs, 1979; 6 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Contains photographs for book on Blackglama (Fur) Story. Photographs include: 2, 11"x12 1/2"; 4, 2 1/2"x2 1/4".
      Blackglama Story published book in located in series 12; box/folder 27/3.
  - Photographs: 1980s, Subseries 5.; 1 boxes
    Content arranged in chronological order
    This sub-series contains assorted photographs from the 1980s.
    - Portrait photographs, undated; 2 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Portraits of Carol Burnett.
    - Portraits photographs, [1980s]; 9 photographs; 8"x10", b/w & color (Box 60, Folder 14)
      Contains portrait photographs of Carol Burnett. One photo of Burnett and unidentified woman.
  - Photographs-1990s, Subseries 6.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains assorted photographs from the 1990s.
    - Portrait photographs, [1990s]; 2 photographs; 8"x10", b/w (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Contains portraits of Carol Burnett.
    - Photographs, [1990s]; 18 photographs; various sizes, b/w, color (Box 60, Folder 15)
      Contains photographs and 2 photographic slide of Carol Burnett on and off-stage at various events and predominately television performances. Includes photograph of Burnett with Tony Bennett.
    - Portrait negatives, 1991, 1992; 6 negatives; 8"x10", b/w (Box 60, Folder 19)
      Contains portrait negatives of Carol Burnett. Prints of these negatives in box 60, folder 20.
    - Portrait photographs, 1991, 1992; 17 photographs; various sizes, b/w (Box 60, Folder 20)
      Contains portrait photographs of Carol Burnett. Negatives of these prints are in box 60, folder 19.
    - Portraits photographs, [1990s]; 11 slides; 35mm, color (Box 60, Folder 16)
      Contains slide portraits of Carol Burnett.
    - Production slides, [1990s]; 8 slides; 35 mm, color (Box 60, Folder 22)
      Contains slides from an unidentified production.
  - Photographs--2000, 2000s; Subseries 7.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains assorted photographs from the 2000s.
    - Photograph, CBS at 75, 2003; Matted photograh, 22 1/2" x 19", color (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Matted photograph of well-known actors/actresses at CBS studio.
    - Photograph, CBS at 75, 2003; Matted photograh, 22 1/2" x 19", color (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Matted photograph of well-known actors/actresses commemorating CBS 75th anniversary.
- Press Clippings, 1955-2000s; Series 7.; 11 boxes
  This series includes press clippings that are arranged chronologically and are not necessarily related to a specific Carol Burnett project. Researchers looking for press clippings pertaining to a specific show, should also see titles in Series 2: Stage and Live Performances, Series 3: Television Projects, as well as Series 7: Press Clipping under the year(s) of the production.
  Contents are arranged in chronological order; folders a generally arranged by year.
  - Press clippings, 1954-1957; Loose press clippings (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Press clippings from newspapers, industry trade journals and magazines. Some mentions include Burnett's performance in the all women, live stage revue Rehearsal Club Show (1955): and TV show Stanley (1957). Clippings not arranged in any order.
  - Press clippings: 1950-1959, Subseries 2.; 1 boxes
    This sub-series contains press clippings related to productions featuring Carol Burnett such as: "Love Thy Coach" (UCLA), "Stumptown Players," "Rehearsal Club Revue," "Once Upon a Mattress."
    - Press clippings, Carol Burnett, 1955-1959; 1 folder; loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Contains loose press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: UCLA show Love Thy Coach; Stumptown Players; Rehearsal Club Revue, Once Upon a Mattress.
  - Press clippings: 1960-1969, Subseries 3.; 4 boxes
    Contents arranged in chronological order by year.
    This sub-series contains press clippings from 1960-1969 related to Carol Burnett including theater, television and film projects: "The Gary Moore Show," "Once Upon a Mattress," "Who's Been Sleeping in My Bed," "Fade Out, Fade In," "Carol and Company," "Calamity Jane," "Julie and Carol at Carnegie Hall," and "The Carol Burnett Show."
    - Press clippings, 1960; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 2)
      Contains press clippings related to The Gary Moore Show and Once Upon a Mattress.
    - Production company contact information, [1960]; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Contains envelope that was found in original box of press clippings. Address on envelope is: Martin Goodman Productions, Inc. 36 Central Park South New York 19, N.Y.
    - Press clippings, 1961; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Contains press clipping related to Carol Burnett including: The Gary Moore Show.
    - Some Young People in Show Business, press clippings, [1961]; 1 folder; loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Contains press clippings for a feature article (publication unknown) entitled Some Young People in Show Business.
    - Press clippings, 1962; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 18, Folder 11)
      Contains press clippings for Carol Burnett including: performance at the Hotel Sands, Las Vegas; divorce from first husband Don Saroyan; Calamity Jane; performance at Dallas Musical Hall.
    - Press clippings, 1962; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: The Gary Moore Show, Julie and Carol at Carnegie Hall, Emmy win (for Gary Moore Show), Carol and Company, Calamity Jane.
    - Press clippings, 1963; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 6)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: Calamity Jane; Peabody Award; Julie and Carol at Carnegie Hall; Who's Been Sleeping in My Bed.
    - Press clippings, 1964; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including Fade Out, Fade In.
    - Press clippings, 1965; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Press clippings, 1966; 1 folder; loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 1)
      Contains press clipping for Carol Burnett including CBS television special with Lucille Ball and Zero Mostel.
    - Press clippings, 1966; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 43, Folder 1)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including CBS television special with Lucille Ball and Zero Mostel.
    - Press clippings, 1967; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Contains press clipping related to Carol Burnett including: guest appearance on the Lucy Show, Get Smart; birth of daughter Jody Hamilton; performing with Jim Nabors for military bases.
    - Press clippings, 1967; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Contains press clipping related to Carol Burnett including first season of the Carol Burnett Show on CBS.
    - Press clippings, 1967; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Press clippings, 1967; 1 folder, 4 envelops of smaller, loose clippings (Box 43, Folder 2)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: guest appearance on TV show Our Place; party for Burnett hosted by Rock Hudson.
    - Press clippings, 1967; 1 folder; 2 envelops of loose clippings (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Contains press clippings related to feature film Up the Down Staircase starring Sandy Dennis.
    - Press clippings, 1967; 1 folder; loose clippings (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Contains press clippings not related to Carol Burnett; several pertaining to Shirley MacLaine.
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 6)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including the Carol Burnett Show.
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 7)
      Contains press clippings related to general news about Carol Burnett.
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Contains press clippings related to general news regarding Carol Burnett.
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: the Carol Burnett Show and television guest appearances on Girlfriends and Nabors.
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: the Carol Burnett Show, television guest appearances on Girlfriends and Neighbors, The Don Rickles Show.
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 44, Folder 3)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: the Carol Burnett Show, guest television appearance on a Lucille Ball special, birth of daughter Jody Hamilton.
    - Press clippings, 1968; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Contains press clippings related to Carol Burnett including: the Carol Burnett Show, birth of daughter Jody Hamilton.
    - Press Clippings, 1969; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Press clippings, 1969; 1 folder, loose clippings (Box 44, Folder 6)